## Changho Shin

cshin23@wisc.edu https://ch-shin.github.io 1210 W Dayton St, Madison, WI 53706

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research is focused on **foundation models**, including **large language models** and **multimodal foundation models**. Much of my work aims to efficiently help these models adopt new skills. This involves two prongs: (1) **approaches for obtaining and selecting fine-tuning data**, often by using a strategy called **weak supervision** and (2) **efficient adaptation**, including training-free approaches like **model editing**.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### University of Wisconsin-Madison

Sep. 2020 -

- Ph.D. Computer Science, M.S. Mathematics
- Advisor: Professor Frederic Sala

#### Seoul National University

Mar. 2015 – Feb. 2017

- •M.S. Machine Learning
- Advisor: Professor Wonjong Rhee

#### Seoul National University

Mar. 2011 - Feb. 2015

- B.A. in Psychology, B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering
- Graduated with honors (Cum Laude)

# HONORS & AWARDS

# Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship Finalist2024Best Paper Award Honorable Mention (NeurIPS R0-FoMo Workshop)2023NeurIPS 2023 Scholar Award2023Winner in DataComp competition (Filtering Track, Small)2023

### CONFERENCE PUBLICATIONS

- [C1] Dyah Adila\*, Changho Shin\*, Linrong Cai, Frederic Sala, "Zero-Shot Robustification of Zero-Shot Models With Auxiliary Foundation Models", International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2024.
  Workshop version [W1]: Best Paper Award Honorable Mention, Oral Presentation at NeurIPS 2023 R0-FoMo Workshop.
- [C2] Changho Shin, Sonia Cromp, Dyah Adila, Frederic Sala, "Mitigating Source Bias for Fairer Weak Supervision", Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2023.
- [C3] Changho Shin, Winfred Li, Harit Vishwakarma, Nicholas Roberts, Frederic Sala, "Universalizing Weak Supervision", International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2022.
- [C4] Changho Shin, Sunghwan Joo, Jaeryun Yim, Hyoseop Lee, Taesup Moon, Wonjong Rhee, "Subtask Gated Networks for Non-Intrusive Load Monitoring", AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2019.

#### JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

- [J1] Changho Shin, Eunjung Lee, Jeongyun Han, Jaeryun Yim, Hyoseop Lee, Wonjong Rhee, "The ENERTALK Dataset, 15 Hz Electricity Consumption Data from 22 Houses in Korea", *Nature Scientific Data*, 2019 (Impact Factor = 5.929).
- [J2] **Changho Shin**, Seungeun Rho, Hyoseop Lee, Wonjong Rhee, "Data Requirements for Applying Machine Learning to Energy Disaggregation", *Energies*, May 2019 (Impact Factor = 2.707).

### WORKSHOP PUBLICATIONS

- [W1] Dyah Adila\*, **Changho Shin\***, Linrong Cai, Frederic Sala, "Foundation Models Can Robustify Themselves, For Free", NeurIPS 2023 R0-FoMo Workshop. **Best Paper Award Honorable Mention, Oral Presentation**.
- [W2] Changho Shin\*, Joon Suk Huh\*, Elina Choi, "Pool-Search-Demonstrate: Improving Data-wrangling LLMs via better in-context examples", NeurIPS 2023 Table Representation Learning (TRL) Workshop. Oral Presentation.

- [W3] Changho Shin\*, Tzu-heng Huang\*, Sui Jiet Tay, Dyah Adila, Frederic Sala, "Multimodal Data Curation via Object Detection and Filter Ensembles", ICCV 2023 Datacomp Workshop (Rank #1 in DataComp competition filtering track (small)).
- [W4] Changho Shin, Alice Schoenauer-Sebag, "Can we get smarter than majority vote? Efficient use of individual rater's labels for content moderation", NeurIPS 2022 Workshop: Efficient Natural Language and Speech Processing (ENLSP), 2022.

#### **PREPRENTS**

[P1] Changho Shin, Jitian Zhao, Sonia Cromp, Harit Vishwakarma, Frederic Sala, "OTTER: Improving Zero-Shot Classification via Optimal Transport", Under Review, 2024.

#### JOB **EXPERIENCE**

#### Twitter, San Francisco, USA

Jun. 2022 – Aug. 2022

ML Engineer Intern

- Mentor: Alice Schoenauer Sebag Manager: Milind Ganjoo
- Improving toxicity classification via weak supervision [W4]

#### Encored Technologies, Seoul, Korea

Jan. 2018 - Jul. 2020

Data Scientist

- Advisor: Dr. Hyoseop Lee
- Non-intrusive load monitoring [C4, J1, J2], Energy forecasting

Korea Institute for Defense Analyses, Seoul, Korea Jan. 2017 – Dec. 2017 Researcher

#### **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

#### University of Wisconsin-Madison

• Teaching assistant for CS 839 (Foundation Models)

Fall 2023

- Teaching assistant for CS 300 (Programming II)
- Fall 2022, Spring 2023 Fall 2021, Spring 2022
- Teaching assistant for CS 760 (Machine Learning)
- Teaching assistant for CS 320 (Data Programming II)
- Spring 2021
- Teaching assistant for CS 220 (Data Programming I)

#### Fall 2020

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### Machine Learning / Deep Learning / Data Science

PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, scikit-learn, NumPy, Pandas, SciPy

#### **DBMS**

MySQL, MongoDB, PySpark

#### Research & Development Tools

Jupyter, PyCharm, Docker, GitHub, CircleCI, Shell, Amazon Web Services

#### Programming Languages

Python, R, MATLAB, Java, Go, C, LATEX